Mugdha Honrao (1) Featured

Senior Software Developer with 8 + exp in Java .J2EE.Restful API,Spring Core,Spring Boot, Batch, Hibernate, Oracle, Microservices, Banking Domain and have basic knowledge of Angular



Current Designation: Senior Associate Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: More than 3 Months Current Company: Cognizant

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Other International Location

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Core Java, Java8, J2EE, Restful API, Spring Core, Spring

Boot, Batch, Hibernate, Oracle, Microservices, Eclipse, JIRA, Banking Domain and have basic knowledge of Angular

Frontend, Banking, Angularjs

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

To work in the most challenging position with an organization that provides ample opportunities to learn and to contribute.

IT professional with 8+years hands-on experience in Java/J2EE, SpringBoot Development.

Basic understanding in the Banking & Finance domain.

Ability to work independently. Ability to understand and work on new technologies quickly.

Good Analytical and problem solving skills

Work Experience

Cognizant as Senior Associate

Oct 2015 to Till Date

Project Title Bank IntegrationProject -Personal Banking- IBMB Backend services

Location Client Location - Abu dhabi, UAE (Cognizant) And Pune

Duration ONSITE - AUGUST 2017 TILL MAY 2019

OFFSHORE ODC Pune - JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

My Role Associate - Development Oct 2019 - Senior Associate - Development

Domain Banking

Technologies Core Java/java 8, Spring Boot, Rest, JPA, Spring batch, oracle db

Server WAS and Apache Tomcat

Database Oracle 12g Description of the Project

Worked on internet and mobile banking backend services.

- Personal Banking features
- SMS functionality
- **PushNotifications**
- Bank Integration Project -Mule ESB and Java services related to Payments and Personal Banking **Project Title** Client Location - Abu dhabi, UAE (Cognizant) Location

ONSITE - May 2017-JULY 2018 Duration

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1af2f632967eef33c92c4e3555b7d6d2095f5c041b125d155743490c0b0...

My Role Associate - Development

Domain Banking

Technologies Core Java ,Active MQ, Mule Based application services (3.8)

Server Mule Server
Database Oracle 10g
Description of the Project

Payments and Personal Banking related Middleware Application-

Worked on different payments middleware services like -

Card Operating platform - Balance Transfer and Quick Cash

One time SI payment service

RealtimeCard Payment Services

3. Project Title Channel Integrator

Location Cognizant, Pune- UAE Client-Pune Offshore ODC

Duration October -2015 - May 2017 My Role Associate - Developer

Domain Banking

Technologies Core Java, JSP, Servlets, Jasper reports.

Server Apache Tomcat Database Oracle 10g Description of the Project

Channel integrator project serves as a middle ware to the bank's core banking software and different channels like ATM,IB,IVR,SMS,etc.

Worked on different modules like Middleware for ATM Banking
Internet Banking- Retail and Corporate
Middleware for IVR service
SMS Banking
Backend Services - Sync, Alertgenerators, SAF

Yardi Software India Pvt Ltd as Programmer II

Aug 2013 to Sep 2015

4. Project Title Property Management - Procure to Pay (P2P)

Location Yardi Software Pvt Ltd, Pune

Duration AUGUST 2013- SEPTEMBER 2015

My Role Java Programmer Domain Property Management

Technologies Java, JSP, Servlets, Webservices, SOA, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Server Apache Tomcat Database Oracle Description of the Project

P2P application for Property managers automates invoice incoming and processing task. It also provides Shopping marketplace for property managers integrated with company product Voyager. It allows property managers using Voyager to purchase items for their properties, keep track of inventories, PO, Invoices etc. It provides -

Invoice Scanning and Processing

Contract Management

PO Management

Shopping marketplace

RFP Management

P2P thus provides complete end-to-end solution to property managers

Vspace Software as Software Developer

Aug 2011 to Jan 2013

Project Title Content Management Service for JGCC client

And PMPFor Sure

Location Vspace Software, Pune

Team Size 4 My Role Developer Duration 2011-13

Technologies Core Java, JSP, Servlets, CSS, JS, Mysql, Apache Tomcat 6.0, Eclipse

Description of the Project

Client had a need for a WYSWIG tool that allows for easy editing throughout their website. They required a custom CMS

tool. It consisted of admin section as well as member section management.

PMPForSure- A web site for the preparation of PMP certification.

Provides suite of products which includes mocktests and reference books for the preparation of exam.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Pune University in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Full Stack Developer

Udemy Full stack development course

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Core java/java 8, Servlets, JSP			
JDBC, HTML, CSS, JSON, Angular			
Spring Core,Spring Rest,Spring Boot			
Hibernate, Subversion,RTC,Git bitbucket			
Maven , PL/SQL Developer, Eclipse,			
Windows, Linux, HPQC, JIRA, Oracle10g			
UML, Data Structure, XML, Java			
Putty, Log4j ,WinSCP, FileZilla			
restful webservices			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

Affirmative Action

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization